- [Instructor] The Recoil API is very similar
to the React useState Hook,
except that it takes a RecoilState instead
of a default value as arguments.
So let's see how it works.
We're going to see an example right here.
So you're going to make sure that you add
to the scope of your projects, useRecoilState,
and the way that you define it,
it's going to be very similar to the React's useState.
So instead here,
instead of the default value,
it's going to be the atom that we have defined earlier.
And it's going to be the same as with useState.
It's going to return an array
with the first element being the current value of the state.
And the second element is the setup function
that we use to update the value
of the given state when it is called.
And so this hook useRecoilState will subscribe
to the components,
will subscribe to the state, which is contains in the atom,
so the component re-renders
for any change in the requested states.
So let's go back to our startup project.
Here the goal will be to replace the current useState
that we have listed inside the App component.
So we have several of them.
And instead, we're going to use the hook useRecoilStates
to subscribe to the state, which are contained in atoms.
And so this will allow to read
and update the state with useRecoilState,
which has a similar syntax of the useState.
So we don't need to change much right here.
First, we just need to make sure that we add to the scope.
So useRecoilState like so.
Let's go back to inside the App component.
We're going to replace here with useRecoilState.
And instead of adding a default value,
we're going to specify the atom that we have defined,
which will be in this case listState.
Let's do the same for this variable.
And here it's going to be the atom allStates.
For isFiltered, it's going to be filterState.
And there is one last, which is inputValue.
So I'm going to go ahead and add this one right here.
And that's going to be useRecoilStates
and it's going to be inputValue like so.
So that's done for this part.
You can see that now we've been able to subscribe
to the states, which are contained in Atom.
So this is very simple, a very simple process
because the syntax is very similar
to the useState hook from the React API.
Next, we see how to create derived data
from the state with selectors.